{"tossups": [{"question": "In this city, a dramatization of the novel<em> The Two Captains</em> was broken up at the start of a terrorist attack. Civilian casualties in this city escalated after troops refused to tell doctors what type of chemical weapon they had used, leading to the death of 130 hostages. The Spetsnaz special forces indiscriminately used poison gas to end a hostage crisis in, for ten points, what city where Chechen terrorists occupied the Dubrovka Theater in 2002?", "answer": "<b> Moscow</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man was forced to step down after the Rua Tonelero incident, in which an assassination attempt was launched on rival Carlos Lacerda. The Integralists were suppressed by this man after they advocated for fascism. This man declared he would \u201cleave life to enter history\u201d before shooting himself with a pistol. During his tenure, he established Petrobras and administered the South American Estado Novo period. For ten points, name this president of Brazil in the 1940s.", "answer": "Getulio<b> Vargas</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This philosopher originated the image of a \u201ctree falling in a forest\u201d with nobody around to hear it as part of an argument that God must exist to percieve the whole universe at all times. That image, which later reappeared in a limerick, comes from this thinker\u2019s<em> Treatise Concerning the Principles of Human</em> <em>Knowledge</em>. This thinker later wrote that \u201cto be is to be perceived\u201d in<em> Three Dialogues Between Hylas</em> <em>and Philonous</em>. For ten points, name this \u201cimmaterialist\u201d Anglo-Irish philosopher who lends his name to a university city in California.", "answer": "Bishop George<b> Berkeley</b> ([BARK-lee], but be lenient)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "This doctrine was used in conjunction with the concept of \u201cbad tendency\u201d in the conviction of a man who published a \u201cLeft Wing Manifesto.\u201d Since<em> Brandenburg v. Ohio</em>, this doctrine has been replaced by the idea of \u201cimminent lawless action.\u201d This doctrine was introduced in an opinion that described the evils of \u201cfalsely shouting fire in a theatre.\u201d<em> Schenck v. U.S.</em> originated, for ten points, what four-word doctrine by which justice Oliver Wendell Holmes described situations in which free speech was not protected by the Constitution?", "answer": "<b> clear and present danger</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A song about this structure included a chorus with the lines \u201cAnd you\u2019ll always know your neighbor / And you\u2019ll always know your pal\u201d and was written by Thomas Allen. Canvass White developed a new type of cement while working on this structure. Cities like May\u2019s Point and Lockport were along this structure, whose construction was opposed by the Bucktails. This structure, which opened in 1825, passed through the Mohawk Valley. DeWitt Clinton commissioned, for ten points, what canal running from Buffalo to Albany?", "answer": "<b> Erie Canal</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Four canvases featuring depictions of this figure had bullets driven through them by Dorothy Podber. The last professional photograph of this figure features a kiss blown on a Santa Monica beach. Replica artist Elaine Sturtevant used an original still from the film<em> Niagara</em> for a depiction of this woman that was inspired by fifty silk-screen prints created by Andy Warhol. The first cover of<em> Playboy</em> magazine featured, for ten points, what actress, born as Norma Jeane Mortenson?", "answer": "Marilyn<b> Monroe</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "Prior to this event, Avner Less was placed in charge of interrogations. This event led to an execution that took place at Ramla. Robert Servatius led the defense in this trial, which led Hannah Arendt to coin the term \u201cbanality of evil\u201d to describe the use of the \u201cfollowing orders\u201d defense. This event was made possible by Mossad\u2019s capture of its subject in Argentina. For ten points, name this 1962 trial of a Nazi leader in Israel.", "answer": "<b> trial</b> of Adolf<b> Eichmann</b> (\u201dtrial\u201d not needed after it is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This composer depicted the 1994 Los Angeles earthquake in<em> I Was Looking at the Ceiling and Then</em> <em>I Saw the Sky</em>. An opera by this composer begins with the \u201cChorus of Exiled Palestinians\u201d and the\u201cChorus of Exiled Jews\u201d and centers on the hijacking of the cruise ship<em> Achille Lauro</em>. The ballet \u201cThe Red Detachment of Women\u201d is featured in an opera by this composer that begins with the title character stepping of<em> The Spirit of \u201876</em>. For ten points, name this American minimalist composer of<em> Nixon in China</em>.", "answer": "John Coolidge<b> Adams</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Opera"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>One side in this battle was bolstered by the arrival of John George\u2019s forces, though those Saxon troops were later routed. During this battle, Johan Baner\u2019s cavalry routed the Black Cuirassiers, who weren\u2019t given the proper authority to charge and attacked because of the</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>myth that a Pappenheim would save Germany from an invading king. The losing side</b> <b>in this battle was forced to rehire Albrecht (*)</b> Wallenstein to cover for the wounded Count Tilly. For ten points, name this 1631 battle fought near Leipzig, a great victory for Gustavus Adolphus in the Thirty Years\u2019 War.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Breitenfeld</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Members of this tribe sacked the town of Linville during the Great Raid of 1840, which may have been in retaliation for an incident in which twelve of their leaders were killed during peace talks, the Council House Fight. The Kiowa and this tribe agreed to relocate</b> <b>to smaller reservations as part of the first (+)</b> <b>Medicine Lodge Treaty. Buffalo Hump and</b> <b>Medicine Lodge Treaty. Buffalo Hump and</b> <b>Quanah Parker were prominent leaders of the tribe, which often clashed with (*)</b> <b>Quanah Parker were prominent leaders of the tribe, which often clashed with (*)</b> Texans throughout the nineteenth century. For ten points, name this tribe sometimes called the \u201cLords of the Southern Plains.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Comanche</b> Page 9", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "After strife between the prefect Orestes and the patriarch (+) Cyril broke out, this thinker was labeled a heretic and murdered by a Christian mob in 415 AD in (*) </b> her hometown of Alexandria, making her a martyr for future philosophers. Ptolemy\u2019s<em> Almagest</em> was edited by, for ten points, what Neoplatonist philosopher and mathematician?", "answer": "<b> Hypatia</b> of Alexandria", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<b>Eight howitzers were left buried in what is now this state during a Civil War retreat led by Henry Hopkins Sibley a few weeks after the Battle of Glorieta Pass here. A pair of cities in Kansas and a city in this state name the ATSF Railway; the same city names a (+) trail</b> <b>blazed by William Becknell that linked with El Camino Real. This state\u2019s (*)</b> Alamogordo Bombing Range was used for the Trinity test in 1945. The easternmost land of the Gadsden Purchase is now the southernmost land of, for ten points, what state where the Roswell UFO crash supposedly happened to the southeast of Albuquerque?", "answer": "<b> New Mexico</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This leader\u2019s navy was damaged when John Vassall was blackmailed into being a Soviet spy. Though this politician began the Polaris nuclear project, he ended the National Service and joined the USSR and United States as the third major country to sign the Partial Test</b> <b>Ban Treaty. This man\u2019s (+)</b> <b>cabinet was rocked by the revelation that Christine Keeler</b> <b>had an affair with the Secretary of State for War, John Profumo. This Prime Minister\u2019s (*) </b> sub-Saharan tour of Africa is credited with speeding up decolonization. For ten points, name this Conservative Prime Minister of the UK who gave the 1960 \u201cWind of Change\u201d speech in South Africa.", "answer": "Harold<b> MacMillan</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Curly Harris attempted to mitigate the financial losses caused by this event by having three of his employees dress in street clothes and act as customers. David Richmond and Ezell Blair were among the participants in this event, who were attendees of an (+) Agricultural and Technical State University. After buying toothpaste, the four initial members of this event unsuccessfully tried to order a (*)</b> cup of coffee as employees appealed to a \u201cwhites only\u201d policy. For ten points, name this 1960 event in which African-American students occupied a Woolworth lunch counter in North Carolina.", "answer": "1960<b> Greensboro sit-in</b>s (prompt on partial answers) Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}